

# Deepanchakravarthi Venkatachalapathi Dotnet Fullstack

Ocimbatore

☑ deepanmotog@gmail.com

**&** +91 8825504441

## SOCIAL

in @deepan-v-637a801a0

## PROFILE

Expert in developing web applications using Asp.Net core API with Angular and React. Proficient in microservices architecture. Proficient in developing Asp.Net MVC architecture applications. Proficient in Entity framework with Sql/NoSql. Good knowledge in Azure DevOps and Azure Services. Good Knowledge in Docker and Kubernetes. 2 years of Onsite experience in the Netherlands. Proficient in debugging issues and finding solutions. Successfully delivering projects as a technical team lead.

# EDUCATION

SSLC

Board of Secondary Education, Salem,India 2001-2002

# Diploma in Electronics

Department of Technical Education, Salem, India 2003-2006

## EXPERIENCE

# Specialist

May 2022 | Lnt Infotech | Coimbatore, India

I lead a team of 3 API developers where we create API services developed in Microservices architecture that communicates to another one of Client's data source and produce responses. The portal creates engagements by uploading the relevant data bulk/partially. These engagements are further approved by the engagement partners team. The approved engagements are further stored back to the client's data source again.

# Application Development Team Lead

July 2021 - May 2022 | Accenture, India

I have led the team of four with Angular and AspDotNetCore API as a backend specialized team to the successful delivery of the iAPM project. iAPM helps the customer to assess their projects functionally and cost wise. I have also done the data anonymization and Sonarcube integration in devops pipeline for ICS project. And I have created APIs which creates excel sheets of data for the Azure Appinsights.

## Senior Associate

Sep 2019 - Jul 2021 | CTS, Chennai, India

Successfully led a project of creating a production like environment. Successfully formed a team for enhancements work and led them for many successful deliveries. Did proof of concepts with Azure Chatbot and data analysis and presented them to the clients. Initiated cloud migrations with containerization concepts. Collecting the enhancements and features list and prioritize them based on the Business needs.

Analyze and design them considering the release date. Take each items through test phases like QA, Stage, UAT and Production. Production support. Technical assistance to the team. Driving daily scrum call with internal team. Driving daily client call to discuss on the progress. Release and deployment management starting from Creating the code branch, assigning tasks to the team, checking in the code, configuring the pipeline from the repository to different environments. Deployment support with the Server management team. Monitoring and supporting to ensure applications stability across all the environments.

# Dotnet Developer

Dec 2018 - May 2019 | NextGen Webservices Ltd, Coimbatore, India Create and assign tasks for both internal and external resources, monitoring and managing their daily schedules in real time. I worked as End to end module developer.

# Associate Engineer

June 2016 - Nov 2018 | AJ Tech Research Labs, Coimbatore,India
Below are the projects that I have worked from scratch for various
clients. 1. Python automations. [Sales Analysis, Future predictions, PDF to
Audio, repetitive Emails and WhatsApp messages sending, QnA chatbot,
Speech recognition projects] 2. MERN stack and Angular applications. 3.
ChatBot(Azure QnA maker)

# Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics

SNS College Of Technology, Coimbatore, India 2006-2010

## SKILLS

- Asp.Net Core API
- C#
- Entityframework Core
- Azure Devops and Azure
  Services
- Docker and Kubernetes
- Html
- CSS
- Javascript
- Angular
- React

# Senior Software Engineer

Tech Mahindra, Pune,India

Senior dotnet developer and Onsite delivery coordinator. Responsibilities: 2 years working experience at onsite with clients directly. Understanding the business needs and designing them as design documents. Estimation on the modules with expected delivery dates on each modules. Creating proof of concepts and showcasing them to the clients. Implementing the real business with the every day inputs from Clients.

#### CERTIFICATIONS

## Introduction to Cybersecurity

Completed Introduction to Cybersecurity by Cisco Networking Academy

## **Linux Basics**

Completed NDG Linux Unhatched by Cisco Networking Academy

# Strengthening Our Cyber Resiliency

Completed Strengthening Our Cyber Resiliency by World Bank Group

## **Docker Basics**

Docker Mastery certificate of completion in Udemy.

## LANGUAGES

English

• Tamil

## INTERESTS

